There's no one else who can beat Ekko's rates. Taking everything into account, where
Ekko was offering me 21,000, ICICI LBD quoted me 18,19,000.
They give almost 100% margin to all these dealers and aggregators. So, for an insurance that
should be ₹50,000, dealers will quote you ₹1 lakh. Why not Bajaj Capital? So,
I contacted Bajaj Capital. Okay.
I just spoke directly with Bajaj Capital. When you pay online, you
don't get the scope for negotiation. The price 30 days before will be different from the price 2 months
before and the price 90 days before. You checked
Ekko again . Yes
, it happened just now within 2 months. The price increased.
So it became ₹25,000. If you have a claim of ₹00, you
have to pay ₹10,000 from your pocket. You signed this in the agreement itself. You just don't know. You
don't know.
Let me tell you this: Guys, when you buy your policy and you feel that
the pricing is being quoted unreasonably low, just make sure there
is such a difference in the wallet and what is the reason? So,
first of all, let me tell you, hello everyone and welcome back to the new video.
I am your friend Nikhil and I am back with another new and informative video. So, do
you also use an EV or any other vehicle and now it is time to
renew your vehicle insurance? Then this video is going to be made for you.
I use a Tata Nexon EV, and now that I'm renewing
my insurance after a year, what are the things I should consider?
What are the add-ons I can't afford to miss? Should I
renew with the same insurance company or change? And I'm going
to answer many of the questions you're all thinking about in this video
. So, watch the video completely. If you like it, hit "like" and if you
like it very much, if you haven't already subscribed to the channel, hit the subscribe button and the bell
notification for all future updates. Without wasting any further time, let's
get started. Let's get going. [Music]
So guys, I'm at Eco Park. As you can see,
it's a beautiful location where it's so much fun to make videos for you. But today, it's
such a beautiful Sunday, I thought I shouldn't do it alone. So I
invited my friend. As you can see, there are two Nexons behind me.
So, you'll know why there are two Nexons. But welcome, sir.
Thank you. Thank you for inviting me. My pleasure is Hero Dagda, if you
have seen him on our channel, then his Nexon FILs ownership review was
loved a lot, you can go and watch it on the link I have called Hero Da today
because it is very interesting, firstly I will tell him that
it is time for his insurance renewal, so he said that he has to renew his insurance,
what do I have to do, I said come, I will tell him, firstly
I will share it with him and you too, it will help everyone, secondly recently
Herokd's car had an accident, it was a rear
accident and which company's information do you
use from Acc to Acc, so he
used ACO claim, what kind of response did he get or not, next
video will be made for that, so definitely press the bell notification so that
you get that update. Along with this, I will show you the V2V V2L concept where I
will charge his car from my car. Which product is that? You'll find everything
. But let's continue in this video. Let's get inside the car.
Sit comfortably, or even just stand outside. The weather is nice outside.
Let me show you one thing: how the EV
population is growing. Currently, there are five cars parked in the parking lot.
Parked. So, all four of them are green plates.
Yes. One, two, three, and four. What a thing. So, TVs are increasing. The community is growing. Connect
with your community. We have our pan-India Telegram community.
But these people will say, "Brother, you're dragging the video on too long."
So, let's get to the main point. So, let's get to the main point. Guys, I
bought my Hero car last November 2024. And I took Ekko insurance.
And you also saw my video, if you want to tell me why you
took Ekko insurance? Yes, actually, I have an Ola scooter.
So, I've been continuing with Ekko for the last three years.
Yes. So I had an idea about how much one costs. Then I saw your video as well.
Then, when I checked the pricing at the time of purchase
, the dealers were offering me almost 20,000
to 300,000 less. This is a very interesting point. You
guys often ask me why there's such a difference between Acco and other insurance companies. And if there is,
what's the reason? So, let me first explain why I chose Acco.
Currently, I have Acco insurance on my car. But which one will I renew?
Toward the end of the video, I'll tell you which company I chose,
whether I took ACO or another.
So, of all the insurance companies, I like ICICI LBA. I like
Reliance. Tata AIG is decent.
DIT is also trying to rise. And
you'll see that HDFC, Organon, and so on, all these companies also tie up with dealerships. It also ties up with aggregators
. What are aggregators? Like Bajaj Capital, Policyba
. It ties up with them. And by tying up with them, it
gives almost 100% margin to all these dealers and aggregators. I've done so much research, and
at the time of insurance renewal, I've gained some knowledge. So, don't quote me on this.
It gives almost 100% margin to all these dealers and aggregators. Understand, an
insurance policy should be ₹000. Dealers will quote you ₹1 lakh.
Aggregators will quote you ₹70,000. So why are they doing this? Because they
're quoting with their own margin. One thing I liked about Acko is what does Acko do
? I haven't seen it tie up with any dealership or aggregator yet
. So, their calculations say, "And guys, not a sponsored
video." I have nothing to do with Ekko. I am
not any sponsored video of Ekko. Believe it or not. So what does Ekko do? Ekko says brother I am
not giving money to these dealers. If my clients come to me directly
through my website and app, I will give that 100% margin directly to the client
. So when you go to the dealer, you see
that for example, when you went to the dealer for your Tata Nexon 45, how much
insurance did they quote? It was around 50000. 50000
after negotiating it was 50000. Yes yes
correct and when you bought it from Ek, how much did they charge you,
35000 or so. 50000 35000 correct so what happened is basically Ekko
gave you whatever major discount they had but Ekko does it only for the first year so
if you are going to buy insurance for a new car in my personal opinion there is no one
else that can beat the rates of Ekko as far as the aggregators I spoke to,
at the time of my insurance renewal they also surrendered
saying brother we cannot beat Ekko rates and this is the reason so fair enough but
why Ekko? Recently two-three questions came regarding EV vehicles that Ekko
does not provide electrical short protection. Ekko does not provide any battery protection.
It is true it means battery protection is already inbuilt.
No no people say it is not an add on. It is not. I
enquired before purchasing Ekko. They are saying bumper to bumper means it is totally
covered. And they clearly mention all natural calamities, riots, anything
. Absolutely, if any part of your vehicle
gets damaged, that will be covered under insurance.
What he is trying to say, let me make it a little more technical for you. Acco
also provides its IDV. What is IDV? If your vehicle
is worth Rs 10 lakh, then maybe 7% is deducted and it is 92% or 9% or 3%,
that is some standard. They also provide IDV in the first year. Okay?
Now, the entire battery is also included in that IDV, which includes fire theft, terrorist
activity, rat bite
, natural calamity, water logging, theft, everything. If there is
physical damage to the battery or water ingress, all of that is included. And
I am giving you a screenshot in front of your screen where
we have received this confirmation from Acco's email ID. It's on your screen. Pause
and take a look at it carefully. If you want, you can also send an email in the same way. At the same time,
I have my own consultation service to tell you how to do it.
There's a link in the description. Go there and
book your consultation call. Or call me on the number I've provided. I'll be more than happy to
discuss your options with you. And my buying link for Ekko is also in the description.
You will get it, a little bit of marketing is necessary, that's how I make my
money. Okay, so I was 100% sure when I
bought Ekko and you yourself have done the claim settlement of Ekko, it will come on that. But now let's come
to the second point. So if you want to buy a new car, then according to me there is nothing better than Ekko
. But now what about renewal? I am just sharing my experience
in renewal also . Tell me.
Actually, when the renewal is happening, you can renew it before 90 days. For that
right. So my purchase was on the first of January.
Yes. So last month 30 came within three months
. Then I have checked. Yes. So at that time,
according to different IDB, they were offering 15 to 17 thousand rupees for one year.
So I thought that this is a good price. Within 15,000 to 16, 17,000
in a year, very good, there will be tax on it as well. So let's
pay the actual amount, that is a different thing. So this was it, I was fully
confident that I have got the right Ekko. Same, today morning I checked Ekko again
because I had to come here, so I checked Ekko once again.
Yes. Now this has happened within 2 months. It
had increased. So it has become 25,000.
Three means if I had done it in the first year, that is, in the first month.
Yes, then money would have been saved. Mine was actually 15 and it was not even mentioned there
that the price before 30 days, the price before 2 months and the price before 90 days
would be different, I also had no idea, otherwise
I could have made the purchase in the last month itself, correct, so this
is another point, the policy of my car is going to expire on 5th November, which is just these days, right, and
I had started looking at my insurance a month ago, that's absolutely
right, when I looked at Ekko in the beginning, it showed me 15, 16,000, it
showed me 18,000, whatever will come according to that different IDB,
then it paid and went away, 21,000, but I was still happy and believe me guys, I
had given the money to Ekko, I had made the payment by clicking on the link, then suddenly I
thought that if this is how the information will reach you people, so what did I
do, I first went to Policy Bazaar and said let me see So what's really going on is that
in Policy Bazaar, I got an ICICI LBD with battery protection and consumables, along with
everything else. Well, Ekko also has consumables.
Ekko was offering me 21,000 for everything, but I got an ICI LBD for 18,000.
I said, "I'm saving 20,000 for a
year." Mind it, guys. So I said, "Okay, man, this
is a great deal. There's nothing to worry about." So I said, "Come on, ICICI Long Guard." I thought, "
Wait a second. Why not Bajaj Capital?" So I contacted Bajaj Capital
. Okay.
I just spoke directly with Bajaj Capital. When you go online, you
don't get any scope for negotiation. So always try to speak to someone, because
what did I say? There's a 100% margin. On online aggregator websites, you might find
they're leaving a 35-40% margin. No, but there's one thing you
have to look at. How much excess is being charged? When any company
is offering you a discount at the time of renewing your insurance, you have to look at how much excess
is being charged. Yes,
because I don't remember the name of the company. A friend of mine renewed his
insurance and told me, "I got a very good deal."
The price they quoted was "very good deal." I said,
"Okay, you got a good deal." It's a good deal
with an aggregator, so I bought it online.
Then he filed a claim, and
the claim was for 18,000,
but he only got 2,000 because he had a 16,000 excess in his policy.
Excess means a warranty deduction, which will definitely be deducted from you.
So, let me tell you, guys, when you buy your policy and you feel
that the policy is quoting an excessively low price, just
make sure that there is no warranty deduction and no limited kilometers
. 1000 to 2000 is standard.
It is there in Ekko, in all others I
did not know the concept of 1000 limited kilometers. But right now there is no limited kilometers in Ekko. If
there is any limited, then when you renew your car then keep two things in mind. Firstly
there should not be any voluntary deduction. Voluntary deduction means if you
have a claim of ₹00 then you have to pay ₹10,000 from your pocket. You have signed this in the agreement itself
. You do not know at all. You do not know at all. Exactly the same with him.
It happened. And the
amount of that particular policy was less, maybe 500 km. This was a monthly limit of
500 km to 750 km. If your car has driven 1500 km that month, then
you will not have that claim. So keep both these things in mind. So what did I
do? Then I spoke to a Bajaj Capital agent
and said, "Okay, and guys, you won't believe me, that same
ICICI Longguard policy which was showing me a price of 18,000 in the policy market, they
were ready to give it to me for 16,000." Okay.
Now I got even more confused, and I personally believe that the one thing I personally believe
is seamless. I mean, one of the most modern, their operations are so good
and they have such modern standard operating procedures that just by dealing with them, you
feel like you are dealing with a modern company. I said, "Dude, this
is a dilemma, why should I buy ICICI along with ₹34,000?" I said, "45,000 is enough, it's
a big deal, a big deal.
" I said, "Dude." Then he said, "Sir, why don't you buy Reliance?" I
said, "Yes, tell me, Reliance is also a good company, Reliance General. Now, it
is with Hinduja. It has come out of Ambani's hands and gone to Hinduja, which is Indus
Bank." I said, "Yes, that's also correct.
Tell me about Reliance." The Reliance quote they gave me, "Guys," they
told me, "15 or ₹16,000 with everything—battery pack, battery cover,
consumer, everything." I said, "Dude, how can there be such a margin?" So
what did I do directly? I called Reliance General.
Okay. I called Reliance General, and
how much did they quote me for the SCM policy? Do you know
8 minutes? 28,000. How much are they offering here?"
16,000, they're paying me 28,000. I said, "
Big difference." I said, "Brother, how is this possible? How can the same company, the aggregator,
be paying me less, and you're paying me so much? It's only through all this that I'm
beginning to understand how big this market is, with such huge
margins. So, guys, please, and like I said, if you want to understand
insurance, whether it's a new car or a renewal, please contact me. I
'll explain it to you thoroughly and save you money. I promise." So, I said, "Dude, you're
paying me ₹16,000 there, sir. Please send me a quote for that policy."
I sent them the quotation via email. A few hours later, I was convinced, "How
can 28,000 even come down to 16,000?" You won't believe what I
'm about to say, guys?" I
mean, I had already decided to call Bajaj Capital. Give me ₹16,000, sure. Because there
's a reason. Why not go with ICI? Reliance, let me explain.
Meanwhile, I got a call from Reliance. They said, "Sir, we
won't give you that one-year policy for ₹16,000. What can we do
for you? If you buy a two-year policy from us, we'll give it to you for ₹29,000.
It's a fair deal. It's absolutely a fair deal."
So what did I do? I took the same deal and leveraged it. Leverage it, guys. There
's no problem with that. You should save your money. After leveraging that, I
went back to Bajaj Capital, and they gave me the same thing, ₹1,000 less. So, I
gave them ₹28,000. I'm sharing the two-year policy with you. 2 years
for Rs 28,000 including battery protection, consumables, etc., tyre
protection, key protection, whatever,
everything. One thing I haven't included
is return to invoice. So, this is a bonus for you towards the end of this video, a
tip. Naturally, this is also correct. You are discussing what we
were discussing off camera. If you mean RDB, if I mean a little more
, then there is no point in taking RTI. Let me tell you
guys. There were recent floods in Tok. Yes.
Many vehicles were submerged in that, got totaled.
Yes. One of my friends had a Nissan Magnite
in that . Okay.
And he also had insurance from the same company.
No, he had not taken it from ACO. He had taken it from someone else, I don't remember from just one. He
had taken it. He had added RTI to it.
A new car, 6 months old, got submerged.
Later, I asked Ekko and him, "What 's the point
of RTI?" Guys, what's the point of RTI? It won't be enough just to return the invoice. It's
the return of the invoice and the market value at the time of the total loss. Meaning, you've got your vehicle's market value.
Bought it for ₹1 lakh. After two years, if there's a total loss, and RTI is only valid for three years.
Okay? What if you suffer a total loss after two years
? I have a deal going on for a Tata Nexon. Where
they're offering this ₹17 lakh car for ₹1 lakh. They'll say RTI amount and market
value, whichever is lower.
So, RTI doesn't mean you'll get your invoice amount. This
is what I understand. Now, which company tells you what? It's
not written anywhere, guys. There's so much gray area,
I don't know what to say. So, to summarize this whole thing, because we have to make so many videos
. If you need to renew your insurance, guys, don't rush. If possible,
renew it as soon as possible. If your insurance is due after three months,
actually, this is a new concept. All this didn't exist before.
Isn't it true even with an extended warranty?
You get the most benefit from an extended warranty at the time of purchase. And the higher the price,
the higher the rate you'll have to pay. I knew that already. But this insurance,
because the logic is the same as before, right? Yes. That dealership
would call us 15 days in advance, saying, "Sir, your time is up." They'd send us a link, and we'd buy.
Correct. But just today, I saw, oh, this
new thing has started again. So, if you need to renew, guys, don't
waste your time. First, look at the 90 days, because you'll go back and forth and
go to this person. You'll go to that person. Two 90 days, you can get the best deal.
In my opinion, it's the best deal. And if you don't want to work so hard,
contact me. I will give you a reference to my contact from whom I took my insurance
and now I have developed such a good friendship with her
that she works in Bajaj Capital. I will not take her name obviously but you contact me and I will
make sure that I try to get you the best deal and of course it is a professional service
and I would be more than happy to help you with that but that is about it. So to
summarise this whole thing I was using Acko and I was very very happy with Acko.
I wanted to go with Acko. But then because of a little bit of homework, a little bit
of research I have now renewed it with Reliance General for 2 years at around
28,000 which I think is a cracking deal. Now it is possible that you may not get this deal. You may
get it for 3,000, 32,000, you may get it for less also. I do
n't know. But it depends a lot on your negotiation skills.
You have to be very careful. You have to be very careful about
each clause during negotiations. Otherwise, you could be completely robbed.
Two things must be kept in mind: first, there should be no limited kilometers,
and second, there should be no excess access or ventilation deductions. That's it. So,
how did you renew your insurance? I hope you enjoyed this video. So, that was the
video, and I just thought I'd share it. Now, in the next video,
we'll talk about Hiroda's experience with Ekko. We
'll go over the claim settlement process, and I'll be making many more videos today. Then I'll line them up for you. So,
subscribe to the channel for that. If you liked this video, please like it.
Show your love and support. See you in the next video. More like this very soon. Until then,
take care. God bless. Love you guys. Dada
, bye. Bye. You